GIRIDHARAN PANNERSELVAM

FINANCIAL ANALYST

Passionate and Ambitious individual with 5 years of experience in the field of Financial Data

Analysis, now looking for a challenging career in the field of Data/Business Analysis to

display my professionalism and leverage my talent to the new heights to benefit myself

and my organization to stay ahead of the competition.



CONTACTS:



8012907058



giridaranp@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/giridharanpanneerselvam-97131a50



27, MAHALAXMI APARTMENTS, ANBU NAGAR 4th CROSS STREET, VALASARAVAKKAM, CHENNAI - 600087

AWARDS:

ROOKIE ROCKSTAR AWARD, 2017:

Awarded in Recognition Outstanding New Hire on Production Quality during probation period.

STANDING OVATION AWARD, 2019:

Awarded in Recognition of outstanding contribution to the team and remarkable performance.

EXCELLENCE AWARD, 2021:

Awarded in Recognition of displaying exemplary performance for the year.



PROFILE SUMMARY:

The past five years have been spent working with US clients in the Banking and Insurance sector to analyze business requirements, understand the challenges and deliver automation tools and reports.

Able to handle SQL Queries, VBA macros to interact with visualization tools such as MS Excel, Tableau, and Power BI to deliver dashboards as per the client's requirements.



WORK EXPERIENCE:

FINANCIAL ANALYST AT RR DONNELLEY GLOBAL OUTSOURCING PVT. LTD.,

WEBSITE PULLS, 2021 - PRESENT:

- Teamed up with client to access the carrier website from their server and collect data regarding the documents being uploaded on their websites that are pending for the financial transactions to be processed.
- Contributed to the development of VBA macros to automate the client's access to carrier websites to process financial transactions within the client's SLA.
- Developed a reconciliation metric using SQL to validate the accuracy of financial transactions made through automation versus transactions made manually.
- Preparation of a dashboard using Tableau visualization tool to compare the efficiency of the automation tool versus transactions performed manually, which allowed client to add more carriers.

SENIOR FINANCIAL ASSOCIATE:

INDEXING, 2019 - 2021:

- As Subject Matter Expert (SME), providing the team members with training, instant feedback, sharing updates, clarifying doubts, assuring a high percentage of quality, and maintaining complete data on processes to assist the managers in analyzing the team's performance.
- Analyzed the incoming volumes through emails and developed subject line codes for the emails to automate the CCDM (Client Controlled Data Management Tool) and presenting the data to the clients for review purposes.
- Designed automation macros using MS Excel to clear the incoming volume from CCDM and to allocate the incoming volumes between team members based on

EDUCATION:

MBA IN FINANCE AND MARKETING.

SRM Easwari Engineering College.

2015-2017

CGPA: 7.4

BE IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS.

Kumaraswamy College Engineering and Technology

2011-2015

CGPA: 7.3

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- **VBA** Macros
- MS-Excel Advanced
- MS-Power Point Presentation
- MySQL for Data Analytics
- Python for Data Analytics
- Tableau
- PowerBI
- Sagitta Benefit Point
- Share Point Administration

SOFT SKILLS:

- Innovative Thinking
- Attention to Detail
- Initiative Driven
- Client Engagement
- Team Work
- Team Leadership
- **Problem Solving**
- Patience
- Punctual and Flexible
- Work- Life Balance

FINANCIAL ASSOCIATE:

DOWNLOAD MATCHING, 2018 - 2019:

Researched and developed a new model using MS Excel to track the incoming volume, used data to manage the daily incoming volume within the team's SLAs, and provided valuable suggestions to create a new workflow for this process.

RETAIL INSURANCE AND BANKING, 2017 - 2018:

Selected as a new hire for a pilot project to learn the process and undergone process training under client's supervision, provided extreme support to



|= 🖺 CERTIFICATIONS:

BUSINESS ANALYTICS, BENGALURU - 2022:

Successfully completed the Fast Track Business Analytics course at INeuron Intelligence Private Limited.

INVESTMENT BANKING, CHENNAI - 2019:

Successfully completed a course on Investment Banking and Financial System at **TECHTRONICS** partnered with **TCS ION**.

ADVANCED EXCEL, CHENNAI - 2016:

Successfully completed the Advanced Excel course at SRM Axis Intellects Private Limited.



INTERNSHIPS:

INEURON INTELLIGENCE PVT. LTD., BENGALURU - 2022:

Selected for the Internship Program at iNeuron for the Wine Data Analysis project and actively contributing to the selected project along with the completion of product development and proof of concept (PoC), as well as complete performance and learning goals for the current project.



PROJECTS:

- Presented a project report regarding detailed study on dealer's perception about KANSAI NEROLAC PAINTS on the allied shops, Chennai
- Undergone Organizational study at SRI AMMAN BATTERY INDUSTRIES, Dharmapuri



T EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES:

- Coordinated fun activities and sports activities for my organization and led my team's FUN COMMITTEE.
- Donates blood and plasma on a voluntary basis as an active member of Lions Blood Bank foundation.
- Participated in District and State level Air Rifle Competitions.